Guide to the Thomas Parran Papers, 1892-1968 UA.90.F14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust, XXII.
  - Mellon, 1.
    - Annual Reports, Published (Box 102, Folder 1477)
    - Financial Reports, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1478)
    - Financial Statements, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 1479)
    - Pittsburgh Photographic Library (Box 102, Folder 1480)
    - Educational Scientific Trust of the Medical Society of the State of Pa. (Box 102, Folder 1481)
    - No title listed in finding aid (Box 102, Folder 1482)
    - Minutes - Copies of (Box 102, Folder 1483)
  - Meetings, 2.
    - May 19, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1484)
    - July 9, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1485)
    - September 16, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1486)
    - October 20, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1487)
    - November 17, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1488)
    - December 5, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 1489)
    - March 16, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 1490)
    - May 12, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 1491)
  - Mellon, Meetings, 3.
    - September 28, 1959 (Box 103, Folder 1492)
    - November 16, 1959 (Box 103, Folder 1493)
    - January 18, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1494)
    - March 15, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1495)
    - May 17, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1496)
    - September 20, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1497)
    - November 15, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1498)
    - January 18, 1961 (Box 103, Folder 1499)
    - March 13, 1961 (Box 103, Folder 1500)
    - May 15, 1961 (Box 103, Folder 1501)
  - Mellon Foundation - Documents, 4.
    - Schmidt, Mr. A.W. Copies of Foundations Group Speech, October 25, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1502)
    - Financial Statements, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1503)
    - By-Laws, Deed of Trust (Box 103, Folder 1504)
  - Mellon-Dr. Parran, 5.
    - Mellon - Dr. Parran (Box 104, Folder 1505)
  - Mellon - Meetings, 6.
    - Sept. 18, 1961 (Box 104, Folder 1506)
    - Dec. 11, 1961 (Box 104, Folder 1507)
    - March 20, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 1508)
  - Proposals and Reports, 7.
    - Annual Financial Report, Dec. 31, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 1509)
    - A Proposal to The A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust Planning Western Pennsylvania Conservancy, 5/16/62 (Box 104, Folder 1510)
    - A Proposal to The A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust Ohiopyle Land Acquisition Western Pennsylvania Conservancy, May 16, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 1511)
    - Mellon: Annual Meeting of the Board of Trustees, June 1, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 1512)
- University of Pittsburgh, XXIII.
  - Inauguration Dedication, May 9-11, 1957 (Box 104, Folder 1513)
  - School of Public Health Corres., 1958 (Box 104, Folder 1514)
  - Graduate School of Public Health, Health Law Center (Box 104, Folder 1515)
  - Graduate School of Public Health Dean's Report (Box 104, Folder 1516)
  - Library (Parran Collection) (Box 104, Folder 1517)
  - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (Box 104, Folder 1518)
  - Graduate School of Public Health Population Studies Unit (Box 104, Folder 1519)
  - Graduate School of Public Health Reports, bulletins, etc. (Box 104, Folder 1520)
- Dr. Thomas Parran - Miscellaneous, XXIV.
  - Congressional Appearances (Box 105, Folder 1521)
  - Licensure (Box 105, Folder 1522)
  - References - Medical (Box 105, Folder 1523)
  - Re: Retirement as Dean, GSPH, Avalon Appointment Retirement (Box 105, Folder 1524)
  - Publications, List of (Box 105, Folder 1525)
  - Travel Schedules (Box 105, Folder 1526)
  - Omitted (Box 105, Folder 1527)
  - Passports - Dr. Mrs. Parran; Social Security card (Box 105, Folder 1528)
  - Re: University of Pittsburgh (Personal) (Box 106, Folder 1529)
  - Peaks of Progress (Box 106, Folder 1530)
  - Nuisance letters (Box 106, Folder 1531)
- Rockefeller Foundation, XXV.
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1948-1950 (Box 106, Folder 1532)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 106, Folder 1533)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1952-1953 (Box 106, Folder 1534)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1954-1955 (Box 107, Folder 1535)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1956 (Box 107, Folder 1536)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1957 (Box 107, Folder 1537)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Re: annual meeting, 1957 (Box 107, Folder 1538)
  - Emory University - Actions and correspondence re: grant for graduate program (Box 107, Folder 1539)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - General education Board (Box 107, Folder 1540)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - re: Puerto Rico meeting, 1957 (Box 107, Folder 1541)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Financial Reports (see also General Education Board reports) (Box 107, Folder 1542)
  - Rockefeller Foundation: Cox Committee (Box 108, Folder 1543)
  - Documents (Box 108, Folder 1544)
  - Welch-Rose report (Box 108, Folder 1545)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Reports (Box 108, Folder 1546)
    - Confidential Report no. 203: The Unconquered Plague, March 1961
    - Confidential Report no. 204: Development of the Foundation's Agricultural Program in Africa, November 1961
    - Neutralizing Antibodies for Certain Viruses in the Areas of Human Beings Residing in Northern Natal
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 108, Folder 1546A)
    - President's review, 1962
    - Plans for the future, 1963
    - Grants, 1963
    - Fiftieth Anniversary Dinner, 1963
    - Condensed records, 1913-1960
    - Statement by Trustees on the Fiftieth Anniversary
    - Report from Atlantic Monthly on the Rockefeller Foundation by Greer Williams, April 1964
    - Grants, 1964
- Avalon Foundation, XXVI.
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 108, Folder 1547)
  - Meeting of Trustees, April 16, 1963 (Box 108, Folder 1548)
  - Meeting of Trustees, May 23, 1962 (Box 108, Folder 1549)
  - Meeting of Trustees, February 1, 1962 (Box 108, Folder 1550)
  - Meeting of Trustees, April 26, 1962, June 26, 1962 (Box 108, Folder 1551)
  - Treasurer's annual financial report, December 31, 1961 (Box 108, Folder 1552)
  - Meeting of Trustees (Box 108, Folder 1553)
  - Meeting of Trustees, December 5, 1961 (Box 109, Folder 1554)
  - Meeting of Trustees, March 8, 1962 (Box 109, Folder 1555)
  - Meeting of Trustees, October 31, 1961 (Box 109, Folder 1556)
  - Requests for contributions declined (95), July l-Sept. 30, 1961 (Box 109, Folder 1557)
  - Avalon Foundation agreement (Box 109, Folder 1558)
  - By-Laws (Box 109, Folder 1559)
  - Committee on selection of additional trustee (Box 109, Folder 1560)
  - Contributions, Regular annual lists (Box 109, Folder 1561)
  - Contributions, summaries of (Box 109, Folder 1562)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1958 (Box 109, Folder 1563)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1957 to June 1958 (Box 109, Folder 1564)
  - Expense statements (Dr. Parran) (Box 109, Folder 1565)
  - Finance Committee (Box 109, Folder 1566)
  - Incorporation, Certificate of (Box 109, Folder 1567)
  - Minutes, 1961 (Box 109, Folder 1568)
  - Minutes, 1962 (Box 109, Folder 1569)
  - Minutes, 1963 (Box 109, Folder 1570)
  - Minutes, 1964 (Box 109, Folder 1571)
  - Personnel (Box 109, Folder 1572)
- Institute for Philosophical Research, XXVII.
  - Association Material, 1.
    - Policy and program statements in re Avalon Foundation (Box 110, Folder 1573)
    - Requests, Pending information in re Avalon Foundation (Box 110, Folder 1574)
    - Stratton-Blunt report re: Youth Programs, Avalon Foundation (Box 110, Folder 1575)
    - Avalon Foundation 1959-1960 (Box 110, Folder 1576)
    - The National Tuberculosis Association (Box 110, Folder 1577)
  - Correspondence, 2.
    - 1958 (Box 110, Folder 1578)
    - 1956-1958 (Box 110, Folder 1579)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 110, Folder 1580)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 110, Folder 1581)
  - Minutes and Documents, 3.
    - 1954-1955 (Box 111, Folder 1582)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 111, Folder 1583)
- Russia (Public Health Mission to), XXVIII.
  - Correspondence in re: USPHS Mission, 1957 (Box 111, Folder 1584)
  - Correspondence with Russian officials in re USPHS Mission (Box 111, Folder 1585)
  - Report material in re: USPHS Mission to Soviet Union (Box 111, Folder 1586)
  - Report of the U.S. Public Health Mission to USSR, copies of report. (Box 111, Folder 1587)
  - Snegireff Report re. Public Health Mission to USSR, Section I (Box 111, Folder 1588)
  - Snegireff Report re. Public Health Mission to USSR, Section II (Box 111, Folder 1589)
  - Snegireff Report re. Public Health Mission to USSR, Section III (Box 111, Folder 1590)
  - Reference materials (newspaper clippings) (Box 111, Folder 1591)
  - Correspondence in re: USPHS Mission to Soviet Union, 1958 (Box 111, Folder 1592)
  - Reference Materials (Box 112, Folder 1593)
  - Expenses and itinerary (Box 112, Folder 1594)
  - Publicity USPHS (Box 112, Folder 1595)
  - Correspondence in re USPHS Mission to Soviet Union, 1958 (Box 112, Folder 1592)
  - Reference materials (Box 112, Folder 1593)
  - Expenses and itinerary (Box 112, Folder 1594)
  - Publicity USPHS (Box 112, Folder 1595)
  - I.C.R.S. Medical Reports, Fordham University Press (Box 112, Folder 1596)
  - U.S. - U.S.S.R. Exchange Agreement, 1959 (Box 112, Folder 1597)
  - Trip report: Public Health Mission to the U.S.S.R. from the diary of L.S. Snegireff, August to September, 1957 (Box 112, Folder 1598)
  - Report of the U.S. Public Health Mission to the U.S.S.R. and misc. items pertaining to U.S.S.R. trip, 1957 (Box 112, Folder 1599)
  - Diary of U.S.S.R. trip (Box 112, Folder 1600-1600-A)
- Milbank Memorial Fund, XXIX.
  - Minutes, 1956-1961; 1.
    - Minutes, 1956-1961 (Box 113, Folder 1601)
  - Annual Conference, 2.
    - 1955-1956 (Box 113, Folder 1602)
    - 1957 (Box 113, Folder 1603)
    - 1958 (Box 113, Folder 1604)
    - 1959 (Box 113, Folder 1605)
    - 1960 (Box 113, Folder 1606)
  - Correspondence, 3.
    - 1948-1954 (Box 113, Folder 1607)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 113, Folder 1608)
    - 1958 (Box 113, Folder 1609)
- National Vitamin Council, XXX.
  - Reports, financial statements, publications (Box 114, Folder 1610)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 114, Folder 1611)
  - Correspondence (Box 114, Folder 1612)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 114, Folder 1613)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 114, Folder 1614)
  - Annual Meeting, May 6, 1962 (Box 114, Folder 1615)
- Nutrition Foundation, XXXI.
  - Minutes (Box 115, Folder 1616)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 115, Folder 1617)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 115, Folder 1618)
  - Correspondence (Box 115, Folder 1619)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 115, Folder 1620)
  - By-laws (Box 115, Folder 1621)
- Population Council, XXXII.
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 115, Folder 1622)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1958 (Box 115, Folder 1623)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 116, Folder 1624)
  - Minutes (Box 116, Folder 1625)
  - Reports and meetings, 1961-1962 (Box 116, Folder 1626)
  - Meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 116, Folder 1627-1629)
  - Annual report of the Treasurer, 12/31/60 (Box 116, Folder 1630)
  - Meetings, 1959-1960 (Box 116, Folder 1631-1633)
  - Meetings, 1959 (Box 117, Folder 1634-1635)
  - Meeting, (includes copy of Five Year Plan), 1958 (Box 117, Folder 1635)
  - not used (Box 117, Folder 1637)
  - Ad Hoc Committee (Box 117, Folder 1638)
  - Population Control Documents (Box 117, Folder 1639-1941)
- American Public Health Association, XXXIII.
  - Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 117, Folder 1642-1643)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 118, Folder 1644)
  - Committees- Eligibility (Box 118, Folder 1645)
  - Committee on Population Control of the Maternal and Child Health Section (Box 118, Folder 1646)
  - Committee on Professional Education, 1960-1961 (Box 118, Folder 1647-1653)
  - Committees- Professional Education, 1959 (Box 119, Folder 1654)
  - Committees- Professional Education, Subcommittee for Professional Examination Serv. (Box 119, Folder 1655)
  - Committees- Finance (Box 119, Folder 1656)
  - Committees- Governing Council (Box 119, Folder 1657)
  - Joint Committee on Study of Education for Public Health, 1961-1962 (Box 119, Folder 1658-1661)
  - The Development of Public Health Joint Comm. on Study of Ed. for Public (Box 119, Folder 1662)
  - The Development of Public Health - Joint Committee on Study of Health Education for Public Health (Box 120, Folder 1663)
  - Joint Committee on Graduate Education in Public Health, 1959-1960 (Box 120, Folder 1664)
  - Program Area Committee on Chronic Disease and Rehabilitation (Box 120, Folder 1665)
  - Program Area Committee on Mental Health, 1956-1960 (Box 120, Folder 1,666-1,667)
  - Bronfman Priz, 1961 (Box 120, Folder 1668)
  - Lasker awards, 1958-1961 (Box 120, Folder 1669)
  - Sedgwick Memorial Medal, 1961 (Box 120, Folder 1670)
  - Technical Development Board, 1961 (Box 120, Folder 1671)
  - Technical Development Board, 1959-1960 (Box 121, Folder 1,672-1,673)
  - Sedgwick Memorial Medal, 1960 (Box 121, Folder 1674)
  - A.P.H.A. meeting, Detroit, 1961 (Box 121, Folder 1675)
  - Annual Meetings
    - 88th meeting, San Francisco, 1960 (Box 121, Folder 1676)
    - 87th meeting, Atlantic City, 1959 (Box 121, Folder 1677)
    - 86th meeting, St. Louis, 1958 (Box 121, Folder 1678)
- National Citizens Committee For World Health, XXXIV.
  - By-laws (Box 121, Folder 1679)
  - Minutes (Box 121, Folder 1680)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 121, Folder 1681)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 1681)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 1682)
  - 88th annual meeting, San Francisco, November 2-3, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 1683)
  - Correspondence, unitdate>1959 (Box 122, Folder 1684)
  - 2nd National Conference on World Health, Washington, D.C., May 7-9, 1959 (Box 122, Folder 1685)
  - Annual Meetings, 1958, 1959 (Box 122, Folder 1686-1687)
  - Post-Assembly Technical Tours, 1958 (Box 122, Folder 1688)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 122, Folder 1689-1691)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 123, Folder 1692)
- National Academy of Sciences, XXXV.
  - Study of Africa South of the Sahara Minutes (Box 123, Folder 1696-1697)
  - Study of Africa South of the Sahara, Reports (Box 124, Folder 1698-1699)
  - Population Conference, Williamsburg, June 20-22, 1952 (Box 124, Folder 1700-1701)
- New York Academy of Medicine, XXXVI.
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 1702)
  - Committee on Public Health, 1960-1961 (Box 124, Folder 1703-1704)
  - Committee on Public Health, 1958-1959 (Box 125, Folder 1705-1706)
  - New York World's Fair, Medicine and Health Exhibit, 1964-65 (Box 125, Folder 1707)
  - Whither Medicine Committee, Correspondence, 1961 (Box 125, Folder 1708-1711)
  - Special Committee on Medical Education (Box 125, Folder 1712-1713)
- World Health Organization, XXXVII.
  - Pan American Health Organization - Dr. Parran consultant to (Box 125, Folder 1714)
  - Pan American Health Organization - Dr. Parran consultant to (Box 126, Folder 1715-1716)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1957 (Box 126, Folder 1717-1718)
  - Post-Assembly Technical Sessions, 1955 (Box 126, Folder 1719)
  - World Health Assembly Meetings
    - New Delhi, 1961 (Box 126, Folder 1720)
    - Geneva, 1959 (Box 126, Folder 1721)
    - Minneapolis, 1958 (Box 126, Folder 1722)
- Brazil and Venezuela (contains studies of health problems and sanitation, Rockefeller Foundation funded most of the reports), XXXVIII.
  - Brazil and Venezuela - literature, oversize and travel expenses, July 1959 (Box 127, Folder 1723-1726)
  - Brazil - reports, travel expenses (Box 127, Folder 1727-1729)
  - Liberia (Box 127, Folder 1730)
- Japan - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1956; XXXIX.
  - Executive committee meeting - Foundation material concerning Japan (Box 128, Folder 1731)
  - ABCC Miscellaneous - correspondence, bulletins, analyses of autopsies (Box 128, Folder 1732)
  - Report on ABCC - rough draft only and biostatistical seminar notes on "Late Effects of Atomic Radiation on Man?" (Box 128, Folder 1733)
  - Final report and appendices (on trip to Japan) (Box 128, Folder 1734)
  - Tables from Francis Report concerning exposure to radiation in Hiroshima and Nagasaki (Box 128, Folder 1735)
  - Japan: People (lst news release) Itinerary (Box 128, Folder 1736)
  - Dr. Parran's carbons of letters to Japan (Box 128, Folder 1737)
  - Thank You to Japan (Box 128, Folder 1738)
  - Correspondence re: Japan (Box 128, Folder 1739)
  - ABCC - travel (Box 128, Folder 1740)
  - Hastings report - Japan (Box 128, Folder 1741)
  - Keio University - Tokyo (Box 128, Folder 1742)
  - Nagoya - (city, Japan) (Box 128, Folder 1743)
  - Institute of Public Health - Tokyo (Box 129, Folder 1744)
  - Hiroshima (Box 129, Folder 1745)
  - Kyoto University (Box 129, Folder 1746)
  - Tokyo (Box 129, Folder 1747)
  - Nagasaki (Box 129, Folder 1748-1749)
  - ABCC - National Academy of Science, National Research Council (Box 129, Folder 1750)
  - Japan miscellaneous (Box 129, Folder 1751)
  - The Biological Effects of Radiation (summary reports and a report to the public) and Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission (pictoral review), 1955 (Box 129, Folder 1752)
  - Biographical data on Thomas Parran and family, resignation at University of Pittsburgh for Avalon Foundation (Box 130, Folder 1753-1754)
  - Honorary degrees and memberships, 1930s and 1940s (Box 130, Folder 1755-1756)
  - Retirement as Surgeon General (letters) (Box 130, Folder 1757-1759)
  - Official orders for Thomas Parran - U.S. Public Health Service, 1917-1930 (Box 131, Folder 1760)
  - Mexican Agricultural Program of the Rockefeller Foundation and notebook of photographs (Box 131, Folder 1761)
  - Confidential reports of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1943 (Box 132, Folder 1762)
- Oversize folders from regular inventory, XL.
  - Medical and Sanitary Data on Norway (Box 133, Folder 1763)
  - O.F.R.R.O. (Box 133, Folder 1764)
  - Various Booklets on Air Raids, British cities at war, and information concerning casualties and evacuations. (Box 133, Folder 1765)
  - Great Britain (Civil defense, post war plans) (Box 133, Folder 1766)
  - Notes on the Visit to Edinburgh, 1941 (Box 133, Folder 1767)
  - Birmingham and Coventry Data (Box 133, Folder 1,767A)
  - The Diet of the Belgian Population, 1940-1941 (Box 133, Folder 1,767B)
  - London-School of Hygiene and Public Health (Box 133, Folder 1768)
  - London County Council (Box 133, Folder 1,768A)
  - Col. Harrison - V.D. (Box 133, Folder 1,768B)
  - London Water Supply (Box 133, Folder 1,768C)
  - Medical Research Council (Box 133, Folder 1,768D)
  - Willesdan and Ken. data (Box 133, Folder 1769)
  - British Food Mission. U.K. requirements from the U.S.A., 1941-1943 (Box 133, Folder 1,769A)
  - UNRRA- Thomas Parran (Box 133, Folder 1770)
  - UNRRA- Standing Technical Committee on Health (Box 133, Folder 1771)
  - Air raids and shelters in G.B. (Box 133, Folder 1772)
  - UNRRA- Committee of Council for Europe (Box 134, Folder 1773)
  - UNRRA- Standing Tech. Sub. Comm. on Health for the Far East (Box 134, Folder 1,773A)
  - Miscellaneous UNRRA Meetings- Montreal - Oversized, Sept. 15-23, 1944 (Box 134, Folder 1774)
  - Statements on Health Medical Conditions - Atlantic City, New Jersey, November 10-December 1, 1943 (Box 134, Folder 1,774A)
  - International Sanitary Conventions (Box 134, Folder 1775)
  - London - Wales - England (Box 135, Folder 1776)
  - Pan American Sanitary Organization (Box 135, Folder 1777)
  - Inauguration Dedication, May 9-11, 1957 (Box 135, Folder 1778)
  - Population Control Documents (Box 135, Folder 1779)
  - Brazil and Venezuela - literature, oversize and travel expenses, July 1959 (Box 135, Folder 1780)
  - Nagasaki (Box 135, Folder 1781)
- Photograph Collection, XLI.
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 136, Folder 1782)
  - Mission Trip to the Far East (Box 136, Folder 1783)
  - Denver Conference. Re: Tuberculosis, January, 1957 (Box 136, Folder 1784)
  - Fisher Scientific Company - Pasteur Memorial in Pittsburgh, 1957 (Box 136, Folder 1785)
  - Lima, Peru, 1950 (Box 136, Folder 1786)
  - Lima, Peru Pan American Sanitary Bureau, 1949 (Box 136, Folder 1787)
  - Mackintosh, Dr. James M., 1957-1958 (Box 136, Folder 1788)
  - Marquette University Commencement, Milwaukee Auditorium, June 11, 1950 (Box 136, Folder 1789)
  - Mexico, July 12-August 15, 1951 (Box 136, Folder 1790)
  - Mexico, August 23-September 10, 1949 (Box 136, Folder 1791)
  - Science And Public Health, Mt. Mercy College, Catholic Round Table of Science, April 26, 1952 (Box 136, Folder 1792)
  - Mexico, January, 1961 (Box 136, Folder 1793)
  - Mellon, Meetings, September 20, 1960 (Box 136, Folder 1794)
  - Re: University of Pittsburgh (Personal) (Box 136, Folder 1795)
  - Peaks of Progress at Kaufmann's, 1954 (Box 136, Folder 1796)
  - USPHS Mission, 1957 (Box 136, Folder 1797)
  - Trip to Russia, 1957 (Box 136, Folder 1798)
  - Postcards from Trip to Russia, 1957 (Box 136, Folder 1799)
  - Latin American Village - World Health Organization (Box 136, Folder 1800)
  - Minneapolis, 1958 (Box 136, Folder 1801)
  - Liberia, 1962 (Box 136, Folder 1802)
  - Japan, 1956 (Box 136, Folder 1803)
  - Wodehouse - CMO Canada, 1937 (Box 137)
  - Thomas Parran, Portrait
  - Laying the Cornerstone, New National Institute of Health Buildings - Bethesda, Maryland, June 30, 1938
  - Laying the Cornerstone, New National Institute of Health Buildings - Bethesda, Maryland, June 30, 1938
  - Laying the Cornerstone, New National Institute of Health Buildings - Bethesda, Maryland, June 30, 1938
  - Thomas Parran, Portrait
  - Financial Meeting of New York State Health Commission, April 22, 1932
  - Staff of the New York State Health Department, 1934
  - Drawing of Thomas Parran by Private Morris Silverstein
  - Surgeon General's Staff, October, 1942
  - Surgeon General's Staff, October, 1942
  - General Steve Simmons, Portrait
  - Thomas Parran, Oath - New York State Health Commission, April 6, 1936
  - International Development Advisory Board, November 29, 1950
  - Governor's Party, 1800 hours - Korea, February 14, 1956
  - National Concer Advisory Council, 1947
  - Laying the Cornerstone, New National Institute of Health Buildings - Bethesda, Maryland, June 30, 1938
  - Saratoga Annual Conference, June 27, 1935
  - University of Pittsburgh - Administrative Officers, 1955
  - Thomas Parran, ca. 1930
  - Thomas Parran at his desk
  - Syphilis, Demonstration - Macon County, Alabama, 1930-1931
  - Walker Gordon and Thomas Parran
  - Dr. Thomas Parran, Surgeon General, U.S. Public Health Service
  - Augustus Wadsworth, 1935
  - Portrait of J. Barros Barreto, Addressed to Dr. Thomas Parran, March, 1939
  - Thomas Parran, Portrait
  - Thomas Parran in uniform
  - Thomas Parran, Portrait
  - Portrait of Edward S. Godfrey, Jr., Addressed to Dr. Thomas Parran
  - U.S. Cadet Nursing Corps., January 1, 1946 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Parade, Liberty, Clay County, Missouri. Dr "Cy" Hunter, Dr. Frederick Reuter, and Dr. Thomas Parran, 1916
  - Don Armstrong, Ted Godfrey, Thomas Parran
  - Thomas Parran Portraits (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Parran Portraits (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Reunion of the Class of 1915, Georgetwon Medical School, Shoreham Hotel, June 8, 1940
  - Thomas Parran, Paul L. Cornell, and Walker Gordon
  - Unidentified People Gathered with Harry S. Truman
  - Unidentified People Gathered Around a Desk, February 18, 1952
  - Photograph taken on the occasion of the lunch offered on Thursday, June 2, 1938, in the building attached to the Palace of the Pan American Union, in honor of His Excellency General Jose Felix Estigarribia, Minister of Paraguay in the United States, by the Director General of the Pan American Union, Dr. L. S. Rowe
  - Photograph taken on the occasion of the lunch offered on Thursday, March 17, 1938, in the building attached to the Palace of the Pan American Union, in honor of Mr. Doctor Eduardo Santos by the Director General of the Pan American Union, Dr. L. S. Rowe